<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>ranting on adonese&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/ranting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ranting on adonese&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/ranting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>And life goes on</title>
      <link>/post/moving-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/moving-on/</guid>
      <description>The fact i still have my ex&amp;rsquo;s gifts is nothing short of a surprise to me. i still have:
 her mug a lovely backpack an oracle speaker pocket shoes jalabya على الله  Up until a few days ago, i kept a present i was meaning to give it to her (though i didn&amp;rsquo;t), before i gave to a friend. The truth is, i suck at keeping things around, i mean even if i want to, it is just so difficult for me to keep things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Date</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-06-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-06-reflection/</guid>
      <description>Just to confirm: i have dated before, i kinda did the whole process so i&amp;rsquo;m very well familar with how dates are practically been conducted. The only problem is i usually was more or less invited to the dates and that what is making things this complex.
Why dating has became more difficult? Or, is it just me? Well, this really and truly is a personal issue, but one way of reasoning about the issues i ran into &amp;ndash; the bugs, is by speaking them out loud (usually to myself or with a colleague / friend, but you gotta do what you got.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Date</title>
      <link>/post/2021-10-22-a-date/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-10-22-a-date/</guid>
      <description>Just to confirm: i have dated before, i kinda did the whole process so i&amp;rsquo;m very well familar with how dates are practically been conducted. The only problem is i usually was more or less invited to the dates and that what is making things this complex.
Why dating has became more difficult? Or, is it just me? Well, this really and truly is a personal issue, but one way of reasoning about the issues i ran into &amp;ndash; the bugs, is by speaking them out loud (usually to myself or with a colleague / friend, but you gotta do what you got.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiring</title>
      <link>/post/2021-10-09-lets-talk-about-hiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-10-09-lets-talk-about-hiring/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about hiring. Also hiring&amp;rsquo;s nuts. i have listened to Mohamed Mudather&amp;rsquo;s video about hiring (Kutti is the CEO of Orooma, popular recruitment company in Sudan). One of the things he mentioned:
 you don&amp;rsquo;t have to have your guy at said company to hire you and companies are struggling to recruit candidates.  So, if that was the case, then why engineers and even great ones are struggling to get hired?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bad practices and dirty code</title>
      <link>/post/2021-10-02-dirty-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-10-02-dirty-code/</guid>
      <description>i&amp;rsquo;m back to writing again. Hooray! Something&amp;rsquo;s been coocked aight?
Today i want to talk about a few things i hate about programming. Lots of enthusiastic programmers fall into this trap that is: 🥁🥁🥁 clean code! I don&amp;rsquo;t know of anything that is as subjective as clean code. You just cannot say whether this code is clean or not. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense at all.
java fuck java. Honestly, whenever i have a conversation with a java developer and no matter how senior they are it is always the same topics: best practices, clean code, and design patterns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let us change the tone</title>
      <link>/post/2021-06-19-ngos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-06-19-ngos/</guid>
      <description>I worked with some Non Government Organizations (NGOs) for some time, not too much to draw any conclusion, but long enough to get to notice some patterns. They are all seem to be well spoken, smart, and have it figured out. They know what they are doing, and they all have this same accent, for the lack of a better word.
The problem when we all have the same perspective, the same way of thinking, the books method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The non-achievers</title>
      <link>/post/2020-12-31-non-achievers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-12-31-non-achievers/</guid>
      <description>So it is a new year, huh? You suddenly find your friends achieving really cool things and you feel like you have not done any thing. This post is for you, for US.
I don&amp;rsquo;t think life is a discrete function, and treating it that way might be the source of this optimizing for dopamine.
Success is not linear, in the journey of your life you will have far more failures than your successes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9-5</title>
      <link>/post/2020-09-04-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-09-04-work/</guid>
      <description>I have not written any post recently (4 months since my breakup post). I want to use this article to discuss some of the ideas i have about &amp;ldquo;work&amp;rdquo;, and by work i mean professional work. I won&amp;rsquo;t be citing anything (at least for now since i&amp;rsquo;m using this post to get away from working so yeah), so take everything here with a hugge grain of salt.
Corona has changed a lot and many of big software companies have moved to a permanent remote work setup.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
