<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>adonese's Blog</title><link>https://adonese.sd/</link><description>Recent content on adonese's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 19:52:20 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adonese.sd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tax Bracket Creep</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/tax-bracket-creep/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 19:52:20 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/tax-bracket-creep/</guid><description>I never thought there was actually a name for this which adds to how fiasco the whole thing is. But back to one of my earliest companies, my colleague had a very interesting encounter. After months of working really hard he felt the need to ask for a much deserved raise. So went by the HR and completed everything and they told him that he&amp;rsquo;ll get a raise as per the company&amp;rsquo;s ladder effective next month.</description></item><item><title>Gallery</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/gallery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 12:57:44 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/gallery/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Side Battles</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/side-battles/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 13:47:52 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/side-battles/</guid><description>If you know me any better you&amp;rsquo;d know that I have been yearning for a mattress for quite sometime now, wrote a blog post about it even 2 years before. And i have been grinding to fix it 2 years prior to that. I have never really fixed it, i know the solution: just buy a damn mattress. Side quests and side battles are important to give you some long due rests and rare sense of victories.</description></item><item><title>Future and now</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/fucurrent/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 14:38:48 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/fucurrent/</guid><description>Thinking too far ahead about one&amp;rsquo;s life while advisable can often yield wrong outputs. A simple strategy would be to diversify your portfolio and invest in a variety of things. Investment here is not strictly financial: time and your own effort are also investments. You don&amp;rsquo;t know what will gonna happen in the next five years from. A good example for survivorship bias to say.
We don&amp;rsquo;t have that crystal clear view, the magic the unravel the future and the secret of the universe.</description></item><item><title>new year</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2024-01-01-new-year-post-war/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2024-01-01-new-year-post-war/</guid><description>Something I didn&amp;rsquo;t share this year yet but I was wondering what did I learn this year. What was the summation of it. Yeah the war inevitably had inflicted serious weight over other things. Surviving that on its own is rather a huge win.
But what I came to realize is that I learned to be much better aware at the things I have had the pleasure to have. That I started to actually appreciate things and to not take things for granted.</description></item><item><title>Oh love oh life</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2023-04-27-oh-love/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2023-04-27-oh-love/</guid><description>O love o life and the question of the spirit. And our constant pursuit to seek absolution.
I no of nothing that keeps me pushing through as though love. The only fuel that drives us onward and upward. But you never really feel its aura unless you have it, you don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily feel how important love can be unless after you are there you are trapped - and only leave a wreck of a sunken ship.</description></item><item><title>No thinking</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2023-04-18-no-thinking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2023-04-18-no-thinking/</guid><description>i usually write quite a lot, it helps me to process things. But this time is quite different though, much more like I&amp;rsquo;m taking a hiatus for good. For someone who overthinks every ounce of their life, this feels different, intriguing and rather enticing. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong and fool it for me using that as an escape from the reality. The war the deaths and the fears lies within. I miss my home, my apartment and my lifestyle too.</description></item><item><title>Being the eldest brother</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2023-04-06-brothers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2023-04-06-brothers/</guid><description>i was talking to online friends recently about what better dictates an older brother. The reponses i was swarmed with was nothing less than helpful and wholesome. Thanks a lot fellas.
Yet my very initial thoughts were unanswered, partly because it is actually me who&amp;rsquo;s supposed to answer them. The question was not really how to become a good older brother but more of why I feel i&amp;rsquo;m lacking.
I will go with the standard template: guidance, support, being present and being there for them.</description></item><item><title>State of payment in Sudan</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2023-03-27-state-of-fintech/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2023-03-27-state-of-fintech/</guid><description>My Experience with E-Payment in Sudan: Challenges and Opportunities I am a cofounder and CTO of a fintech startup company operating in Sudan. Our company aims to provide innovative and convenient solutions for e-payment using cards and POS devices. We believe that we have the right product and the right product-market-fit and we have a solid niche to operate on. However, we also face many challenges and obstacles in our journey to grow and scale our business in the Sudanese market.</description></item><item><title>what makes a company culture</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2023-03-04-what-is-a-culture/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2023-03-04-what-is-a-culture/</guid><description>Sometimes i legit be wondering about life. What is life? What is the whole point? What is the point of living? This is not a question that i can answer, nor is it a warning sign about my mental situation. I&amp;rsquo;m good thank you. But, this mundane, routine thing is becoming extremely irritating. An important person to me used to say that they were a virtual person in the process to become an individual.</description></item><item><title>insecurities</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2023-01-22-me/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2023-01-22-me/</guid><description>This is not me fishing for validation or sympthay. This is just me.
I don&amp;rsquo;t really feel seen. Like honestly, I never felt as though someone actually love me. I always felt I had to put in more efforts and be the giver as my only source and contribution to sustain a relationship. And I was ok with that for the majority of my life. I honestly don&amp;rsquo;t have a dream you know or a goal or whatever, I always just optimize for helping and to some extent serving others.</description></item><item><title>love life</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2023-01-20-happyness/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2023-01-20-happyness/</guid><description>In a retrospect i love life, i have so much love to give and so much stories to tell. i have so many roads i wanna tap into and so many feelings that i yet to experience. Whilst the situation might not really encourage the message this post is trying to relay &amp;ndash; and it might as well seems so off to the point it is irrelevant, given the economical situation we are in at the moment.</description></item><item><title>State of open source in Sudan</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-09-30-oss-in-sd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-09-30-oss-in-sd/</guid><description>I had a delightful conversation with a friend of mine about the state of open source in Sudan, we discussed many topics but the main question was: why open source is not prominent in Sudan?
Software industry in Sudan is not that mature yet, most of what we work on are rather simple crud operations. I feel that we still didn&amp;rsquo;t reach that point where businesses have worked through complicated business requirements that they decided hey let&amp;rsquo;s abstract all of that onto packages and modules we could use by other teams in other projects.</description></item><item><title>BOK and trust</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-09-17-bok/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-09-17-bok/</guid><description>Payment in Sudan is rather a very interesting challenge. But, my focus today is on this rather unique characteristic: trust. I will take Bok, the mobile wallet app for bank of khartoum. It is the largest app in Sudan, backed by the biggest bank in Sudan. It has around two million users, and it became synomyoum to payment in general. If it is a payment channel, then in most case it will be BoK.</description></item><item><title>quiet times</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-09-12-na/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-09-12-na/</guid><description>Today is the first day i enjoyed a quiet night in ages. I went back home rather very early at 330 and took a lovely nap too. Chatted with my friends and roomates, and shitposted on facebook. Now, i&amp;rsquo;m embrassing the nothingness, it is raining and I enjoy the sound of rain in the background, though I also indeed enjoy playing in the rain. I don&amp;rsquo;t have electricity at the moment, but I don&amp;rsquo;t feel pissed for that too.</description></item><item><title>Harsh reality</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-08-27-harsh-reality-check/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-08-27-harsh-reality-check/</guid><description>I notice this general feeling of discomfort amongst my colleagues and friends. Situation in Sudan is not the best, and the grass is always greener on the other side. There are extremely good reasons for that, this is not what this post is trying to address. I don&amp;rsquo;t think life is meant to be comfortable, nor easy. But we can have fun and work our asses while we are at it.</description></item><item><title>Software in Sudan</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-08-13-software-in-sudan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-08-13-software-in-sudan/</guid><description>One of the most commonly used practice for developing software businesses is agile. At its core, agile is a process of iterating on a product. The industry has been heavily relying on agile for years it became the defacto way of building software. Even if a said organization didn&amp;rsquo;t adopt agile, they use some variant of it. What happen when agile fails us.
I have long been keen to collect feedbacks about why tech startups have failed in Sudan.</description></item><item><title>Software takes time. Tradeoffs are imperative</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-07-29-software-takes-time/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-07-29-software-takes-time/</guid><description>Software takes time and it can be quite unpredictable. I built the first version of noebs, a PoC that basically does nothing but acting as a reverse proxy to ebs in less than a week. It took some years later to add some functionalities that we initially created issues for them in ~ 2019. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean we necessarily spent the 3 years just trying to fix that&amp;ndash; simply we shifted our priorities to other issues, or topics.</description></item><item><title>Adulthood, and sins</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-07-01-sins/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-07-01-sins/</guid><description>As a teenager, i grew very conservative. I only had my first girl-friend in first college year. Only to have my first kiss at my first year of having a full-time job, right after graduation. I never really liked parties or going out. A classic introverted person. My 16 personalities test is an INFP so yeah.
growing up Nothing has changed really. I don&amp;rsquo;t smoke, i don&amp;rsquo;t do weed either, nor do i drink.</description></item><item><title>On reading</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-07-01-internet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-07-01-internet/</guid><description>If you ever have a secret book, a secret twitter / facebook account or a blog. A secret place you share your VERY own stuff, please by all means I would be the happiest into being one of your readers! I love reading people&amp;rsquo;s thoughts. This is really the only thing i do so passionately and brings in about huge joy to my life. Books, articles, twitter-shitposting-accounts, whatever that medium that shows that encapsulates the you you!</description></item><item><title>Resignations</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-06-28-resign/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-06-28-resign/</guid><description>I have a decision making problem. I&amp;rsquo;m super good at making on-spot hard decisions. But i suck at making casual decisions: i take REALLY long time deciding between two types of water bottles.
A friend of mine resigned from their job and that took me by surprise. Never in my career had i resigned from my job, really.
2017-2018 first professional employment type: i worked as a part-time TA and researcher at UofK, my contract was for year.</description></item><item><title>Same day, no differences?</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-06-28-paycheck-to-paycheck/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-06-28-paycheck-to-paycheck/</guid><description>I have long since I lost the taste of days. Maybe it is just an age thing and Sudan is also too much. I often would find it too hard to recall what a day in a week we are, and in many cases I would find myself wondering it is actually Wednesday.
Weekends are my chill although I must say, I still find a reason to not chill. I only learned to say &amp;ldquo;Enjoy your weekend&amp;rdquo; quite late in my career in 2019, for me weekends were the bestest times you could achieve more in your tasks.</description></item><item><title>What are we cooking in noebs</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-05-30-what-is-new-noebs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-05-30-what-is-new-noebs/</guid><description>noebs is couple of yours old now, actually next October it will complete its 4th year. That&amp;rsquo;s a lot of years especially in Sudan, software are rather dropped quickly.
what is noebs? noebs is an open source payment gateway. Currently it implements all of EBS services, it supports both EBS Merchant Web Services and Consumer Web Services. It also comes with a built-in support for the new Dynamic Fees model. We also support QR services and the new Merchant Web APIs.</description></item><item><title>Technology is scary</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-05-09-technology-is-scary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-05-09-technology-is-scary/</guid><description>Technology scares me, and don&amp;rsquo;t even get me started on how AI and that crazy shit have serious consequences that we are not adapted, that we have not considered at all. Tech companies emphasized their own revenue over making the humanity better &amp;ndash; errr making its users better. And those incentives don&amp;rsquo;t align with what the actual users want.
For example, a keyboard software. Let&amp;rsquo;s say google&amp;rsquo;s GBoard. It is fantastic, it is smart enough to predict and corrects their typing mistakes.</description></item><item><title>My birthday</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-05-08-birthday/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-05-08-birthday/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m in awe. I&amp;rsquo;m grateful for all of you guys, I&amp;rsquo;m grateful to my parents, siblings, close friends and amongst them my online friends. I will write back about my feelings later. But you made a soul happy.</description></item><item><title>Taking breaks</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-03-18-breaks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-03-18-breaks/</guid><description>I argue engineers and managers to actively seek to shorten work days and work hours. 9-5 / 5 days is such an arbitrarily concept and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t translate at all to productivity, in fact counter to that it is the most unproductive thing we might ever have.
Apart from the common wisdom to avoid burnouts, breaks are really super important. I argue against us having 5-days work scheme. It is way too much, it is quite useless too, and we lose lots of productvity and peak-performance and creative thinking, just to ensure that employees stay longer in the offices.</description></item><item><title>Robots</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-03-04-robots/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-03-04-robots/</guid><description>I argue that people almost turn to the robot mode when they are subject to a very mundane routinic type of daywork. Robot or the executor mode is the safest bet: you don&amp;rsquo;t get to think a lot, you don&amp;rsquo;t get to take risks, you just rebeat and always take-on the easy routes. That is fine and can get things done. You don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily want your Tirhal driver to be creativing about driving&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>A mattress</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-01-14-a-matt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-01-14-a-matt/</guid><description>I just noticed the single thing i have been dreaming to have is a matt. That is ridicluos i know, but I digged a little bit deeper to understand why.
Settlement. The reason i have been so focusing on the matt is that i truly wanted to settle, to have a home and the feeling that comes with it. But i couldn&amp;rsquo;t get anyone.
Now, i actually have the money to buy a matt, a nice lovely good one.</description></item><item><title>what is the point</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-01-05-what-is-the-point/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-01-05-what-is-the-point/</guid><description>Sometimes i legit be wondering about life. What is life? What is the whole point? What is the point of living? This is not a question that i can answer, nor is it a warning sign about my mental situation. I&amp;rsquo;m good thank you. But, this mundane, routine thing is becoming extremely irritating. An important person to me used to say that they were a virtual person in the process to become an individual.</description></item><item><title>A Date</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-11-19-moving-on/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-11-19-moving-on/</guid><description>The fact i still have my ex&amp;rsquo;s gifts is nothing short of a surprise to me. i still have:
her mug a lovely backpack an oracle speaker pocket shoes jalabya على الله Up until a few days ago, i kept a present i was meaning to give it to her (though i didn&amp;rsquo;t), before i gave to a friend. The truth is, i suck at keeping things around, i mean even if i want to, it is just so difficult for me to keep things.</description></item><item><title>A Date</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-10-22-a-date/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-10-22-a-date/</guid><description>Just to confirm: i have dated before, i kinda did the whole process so i&amp;rsquo;m very well familar with how dates are practically been conducted. The only problem is i usually was more or less invited to the dates and that what is making things this complex.
Why dating has became more difficult? Or, is it just me? Well, this really and truly is a personal issue, but one way of reasoning about the issues i ran into &amp;ndash; the bugs, is by speaking them out loud (usually to myself or with a colleague / friend, but you gotta do what you got.</description></item><item><title>hiring</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-10-09-lets-talk-about-hiring/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-10-09-lets-talk-about-hiring/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about hiring. Also hiring&amp;rsquo;s nuts. i have listened to Mohamed Mudather&amp;rsquo;s video about hiring (Kutti is the CEO of Orooma, popular recruitment company in Sudan). One of the things he mentioned:
you don&amp;rsquo;t have to have your guy at said company to hire you and companies are struggling to recruit candidates. So, if that was the case, then why engineers and even great ones are struggling to get hired?</description></item><item><title>bad practices and dirty code</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-10-02-dirty-code/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-10-02-dirty-code/</guid><description>i&amp;rsquo;m back to writing again. Hooray! Something&amp;rsquo;s been coocked aight?
Today i want to talk about a few things i hate about programming. Lots of enthusiastic programmers fall into this trap that is: 🥁🥁🥁 clean code! I don&amp;rsquo;t know of anything that is as subjective as clean code. You just cannot say whether this code is clean or not. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense at all.
java fuck java. Honestly, whenever i have a conversation with a java developer and no matter how senior they are it is always the same topics: best practices, clean code, and design patterns.</description></item><item><title>love</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-10-01-love/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-10-01-love/</guid><description>There is nothing inherently special about love. But it is still there, it hurts us, it touches us deeper than any feeling there is.
I wish i could explain what love is, i wish i could find that right formula to show y&amp;rsquo;all that this is love. But i don&amp;rsquo;t think i have that answer nor that i&amp;rsquo;m interested to acquire that answer anymore. in life you are always just one step further from meeting their love of life.</description></item><item><title>Let us change the tone</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-06-19-ngos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-06-19-ngos/</guid><description>I worked with some Non Government Organizations (NGOs) for some time, not too much to draw any conclusion, but long enough to get to notice some patterns. They are all seem to be well spoken, smart, and have it figured out. They know what they are doing, and they all have this same accent, for the lack of a better word.
The problem when we all have the same perspective, the same way of thinking, the books method.</description></item><item><title>I'm running out of descriptors</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-06-01-fd/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-06-01-fd/</guid><description>Ok, that was really too dumb of me. But let us see how sockets, files, and all that works. AND HOW things go south. I will basically walk you through my thinking process to get into this error.
6:00 AM
I was called very early in the morning from the client. That is usually a bad sign. The client was complaining that the server was down. In fact it is never the server is down.</description></item><item><title>Management, delegation, and people</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-02-21-management/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-02-21-management/</guid><description/></item><item><title>API design</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-01-15-api-design/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-01-15-api-design/</guid><description>This post serves as a walkthrough for noebs sdks. Noebs is an open source payment gateway with large support and adoption from many corporations in Sudan. Our goal is to make payments secure and simple, and we want to do that super fast. To this end, we started rolling out our sdks. SDKs are fancy way of saying libraries, a code that others can import to interact with our services. Noebs sdk is derived from our code, and it is being used in prod for a while now.</description></item><item><title>what is an api</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-01-09-what-is-an-api/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-01-09-what-is-an-api/</guid><description>So essentially your mobile is somewhere, with an ip address right? And we are pretty much familiar with ip addresses, domain names and stuff, we type in google.com and we are welcomed with google search, and so on. This process is technically called http request. Http cause is the protocol that was used to make the request happens, protocol is really just a fancy way of saying &amp;ldquo;hey dude, umm can you tell me how are you going to send me your bytes&amp;rdquo;&amp;ndash;everythying is a byte.</description></item><item><title>The non-achievers</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-12-31-non-achievers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-12-31-non-achievers/</guid><description>So it is a new year, huh? You suddenly find your friends achieving really cool things and you feel like you have not done any thing. This post is for you, for US.
I don&amp;rsquo;t think life is a discrete function, and treating it that way might be the source of this optimizing for dopamine.
Success is not linear, in the journey of your life you will have far more failures than your successes.</description></item><item><title>EEBAx: History</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-12-25-eebax/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-12-25-eebax/</guid><description>I surprisingly had a few jobs in my career. Beside my own startup, i only worked to Ashrafcom. EEBAx was my first startup that i build with Mohamed Jaafar, https://eebax.com.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to go back to ~ 2013 and how it all started.
This website was made by Mohamed Jaafar (the one on the left, obviously 😂), in 2015.
In 2014, i had the shortest conversation with Mohamed. I told him i don&amp;rsquo;t think i can fit into Surveying and I want to shift career to software, in a professional way.</description></item><item><title>Capitalism, software and burnout</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-12-21-capitalism-software/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-12-21-capitalism-software/</guid><description>Or really, publish or perish.
Let&amp;rsquo;s set the stage for this: you don&amp;rsquo;t have to learn a new thing every day. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to produce a fancy thing every day and you definitely don&amp;rsquo;t have to be at your best every day. People are humans, and humans by nature have their ups and downs.
Chill, take some time off. Enjoy the little things, get away from your laptop. You are not a robot.</description></item><item><title>Communications ettiqute</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-12-18-online-communication/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-12-18-online-communication/</guid><description>Text based communication is far more difficult than verbal one. Context is mostly missing, and conversations can get heated faster than in verbal ones.
It makes sense to suggest readers to always assume the best intent and be explicit and ask if they didn&amp;rsquo;t get the intent. But I want also to focus on the writer part. How do you communicate with text in ways that is clear and not rude to your readers.</description></item><item><title>Building against interfaces</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-11-24-building-against-interfaces/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-11-24-building-against-interfaces/</guid><description>This post discusses technical details</description></item><item><title>What are you testing</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-11-10-what-are-you-testing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-11-10-what-are-you-testing/</guid><description>Testing in EBS Ultimately security tests in EBS are meant to assess PCI compliance of an organization, to this end, PCI DSS requirements are:
Install a firewall Change all default passwords on network-connected devices Protect stored cardholder data via encryption, hashing, or other data protection methods Encrypt cardholder data in transit Install malware protection Patch vulnerabilities in all systems and applications Restrict access to cardholder data to authorized personnel Control and restrict system access Control and restrict physical access to cardholder data Monitor access to data Test security systems regularly Maintain an information security policy Let us go through them one by one, they are not that hard eh?</description></item><item><title>Values and pointers: What could possibly go wrong?</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-10-30-values-types-and-pointers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-10-30-values-types-and-pointers/</guid><description>This post highlights a weird and expected behavior we encountered while using Go&amp;rsquo;s encoding/json library.
In go, we pass by value, that really means this:
type User struct { Name string } func changeMe(u User) { u.Name = &amp;#34;New Name&amp;#34; } func main(){ u := User{Name: &amp;#34;mohamed&amp;#34;} changeMe(u) log.Printf(&amp;#34;The user is: %s&amp;#34;, u.Name) // mohamed } To change by value, we must pass a pointer, we can change the code to be something like this:</description></item><item><title>9-5</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-09-04-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-09-04-work/</guid><description>I have not written any post recently (4 months since my breakup post). I want to use this article to discuss some of the ideas i have about &amp;ldquo;work&amp;rdquo;, and by work i mean professional work. I won&amp;rsquo;t be citing anything (at least for now since i&amp;rsquo;m using this post to get away from working so yeah), so take everything here with a hugge grain of salt.
Corona has changed a lot and many of big software companies have moved to a permanent remote work setup.</description></item><item><title>On life and love</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-05-12-self-reflection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-05-12-self-reflection/</guid><description>Relationships are hard to maintain. It touches very deep parts inside you, it makes you more insecure and usually more dumber. Relationships are hard.
It is extremely rare in nature to have two independently actors to align and to keep on that. It is often each partner in a different stage in the relationship than the other. The expectations change and so are the responsibilities. We are human and it is imperative we are insecure and subject to external factor.</description></item><item><title>Simple design: probably a good one!</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-04-08-personal-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-04-08-personal-notes/</guid><description>This article is intended to be rather short ™. I will discuss my latest tool [https://github.com/adonese/ebs-live](ebs live dashboard api consumer). As the name suggests, this tool simply converts EBS&amp;rsquo;s website into an API. Pretty simple right.
the problem we have an html document we want to parse it to extract some text, v We can use Go&amp;rsquo;s excellent x/net/html library to parse the html. html package provides the following:
proper utf-8 encoding html body node traversing (e.</description></item><item><title>Simple design: probably a good one!</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-04-03-simple-design/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-04-03-simple-design/</guid><description>This article is intended to be rather short ™. I will discuss my latest tool [https://github.com/adonese/ebs-live](ebs live dashboard api consumer). As the name suggests, this tool simply converts EBS&amp;rsquo;s website into an API. Pretty simple right.
the problem we have an html document we want to parse it to extract some text, v We can use Go&amp;rsquo;s excellent x/net/html library to parse the html. html package provides the following:
proper utf-8 encoding html body node traversing (e.</description></item><item><title>About Corona Virus</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-03-19-corona-copy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-03-19-corona-copy/</guid><description>This will be a rather short post on Corona Virus you can read more on Wikipedia. My take on corona is from a slightly different perspective, an econmoical one. I&amp;rsquo;m neither a physician nor an economist, so take everything you read here with a huge grain of salt.
You can help yourself and the community a lot by following public health regulations. Cleaning your hands with soap and self isolation can be very helpful in reducing the number of Corona cases and avoid excessively overwhelming the health system.</description></item><item><title>Stereotyping</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-02-09-stereotype/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-02-09-stereotype/</guid><description>stereotyping is bad I do computer programs. i have a long hair, and it is quite usually messy. i fit quite well into the typical computer guy geeks. I have seen many people making that note: hey you look like a geek!
Working on so</description></item><item><title>entrepreneurship the hidden side</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-02-03-enterprneurship/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-02-03-enterprneurship/</guid><description>The gem of this post is that entrepreneurship is not exactly what it sounds, and there is nothing inherently bad about employment. The effort it takes to build a successful startup is far more great than &amp;ldquo;just being an employee&amp;rdquo;. Startups are not actually for everyone, and that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make them any better than well established companies.
entrepreneurship the hidden side I have read so many articles and posts everywhere about startups.</description></item><item><title>On being technical</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-01-20-on-being-too-technical/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-01-20-on-being-too-technical/</guid><description>You are too technical
This week was a little bit fun for me. I had this incident where one of our clients has had a meeting with us and in the process he made joke about my technical skills&amp;ndash;as in they the business owners use us the coders to do their stuff. It was indeed a bad joke, but it led me into writing this post. I wanted to share with you how extremely excited I am of being a programmer and the myth behind &amp;ldquo;technical term&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Airtime</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-01-17-airtime/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-01-17-airtime/</guid><description>Preface A subsidy or government incentive is a form of financial aid or support extended to an economic sector (business, or individual) generally with the aim of promoting economic and social policy1.
MOBILE money in Africa comes in different flavours. The sophisticated sort, exemplified by services such as M-Pesa in Kenya[&amp;hellip;]. This sort uses pre-paid mobile-airtime minutes as a de facto currency that can be transferred between phones, exchanged for cash with dealers&amp;hellip;2</description></item><item><title>How to design libraries</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-01-15-refactoring-and-debugging/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-01-15-refactoring-and-debugging/</guid><description>This post is about how to design libraries. It can help you write good code that you can reuse it in other different parts.
don&amp;rsquo;t do too much We will take examples to make it more clear. When working with Cashqbot our Telegram Payment Bot. We have /rate feature which allows our users to get the USD rate of today Thanks to the folks of price today. I will just go through how we implmeneted this feature and what we can learn from that.</description></item><item><title>A premiere on system design</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-01-04-systems-design/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-01-04-systems-design/</guid><description>We run noebs and it is by far the most feature complete payment middleware in Sudan. Noebs is used by different banks and other payment providers, in addition to us. This post is not about that, I want to discuss more on what is it like to build such a system.
When doing software, we almost always tend to make more features, and many times it is because of the sheer joy of doing so.</description></item><item><title>On the joy of coding</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-01-04-on-the-joy-of-coding/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-01-04-on-the-joy-of-coding/</guid><description>I love coding and I&amp;rsquo;d argue it is one of the most joyful things to do&amp;ndash;it has its rough edges, but still though. If you take joy out of programming it becomes a task, and people often times don&amp;rsquo;t love tasks, or the obligation there of.
I came from engineering background, with some academia background as well. I could not handle acdemia, I wanted to build stuff. Well, after all i&amp;rsquo;m a hacker.</description></item><item><title>Broken systems: e-purse considered harmful</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2018-12-02-broken-systems/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2018-12-02-broken-systems/</guid><description>E-purse Types of cards There are mainly three types of cards, depending on the way money is withdrawn to the merchant&amp;rsquo;s account:
debit card: where the money is automatically deduced from your bank account. It is directly linked to your account, which means you need to have a enough money or an agreed upon overdraft 1. credit card: they are not linked to your account, they allow you to buy things immediatelly and pay for their costs at a later time.</description></item><item><title>A tale of three channels</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2018-11-19-how-to-design-bad-systems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2018-11-19-how-to-design-bad-systems/</guid><description>This post is about systems, APIs, business decisions.
Payment Nearly every transaction involves three parties: a merchant that accepts the card, a bank that issues it, and a payment network that facilitates the transaction between the first two parties. You hear the term PCI a lot.
The standard was created to increase controls around cardholder data to reduce credit card fraud. ~ Wikipedia
We (financial institutions) offer our clients (card holders) these services to ease their access into their accounts.</description></item><item><title>A year at University of Khartoum</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2017-10-28-a-year-at-uofk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2017-10-28-a-year-at-uofk/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always been dreaming of teaching.
I worked as a teaching assistant at University of Khartoum, Geomatics Engineering department. I&amp;rsquo;ve TAed different classes&amp;ndash;mostyl computational/programming ones. It was very nice experience, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more happier. Though, I have some notes.
National Service The national service is the single most evil, human rights violation thing has ever been done. Our governers are literally using us to cover for their economical failures.</description></item><item><title>Internships at gndi</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2017-10-08-internships_at_gndi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2017-10-08-internships_at_gndi/</guid><description>We are very pleased to announce new internships at gndi.
G&amp;amp;I (gndi for short) is a tech company that provides a wide range of geospatial solutions and services for corporates and for individuals as well.
Why is that? This initiatives came as a response to one my posts. Clearly there is a problem in our system. There is no systematic way of getting a job. Every year, tons of peoples are graduating from colleges.</description></item><item><title>gndi E-learning Platform</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2017-06-01-gndi-elearning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2017-06-01-gndi-elearning/</guid><description>E-learning rocks There are several reasons to use e-learning based system as oppose of the classical ones. Hosting all the course materials online can help our students a lot. They will find the materials of the course available 24/7. But that will also help us, too. As an instructor (for both G&amp;amp;I and UofK), I found it to be very time consuming to maintain a class. However, when we moved our works online, things have changed.</description></item><item><title>A friend of mine was faced with his facebook's posts being printed on money papers</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2017-01-23-a-friend-of-mine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2017-01-23-a-friend-of-mine/</guid><description>Money&amp;rsquo;s paper is a special type of papers that only used by authorized companies. It is typically used in the company&amp;rsquo;s official documents e.g., contracts.
A friend of mine (a bad one that actually thinks our governors are villain, screw you anti-progression), he was being summoned in response to his recent posts. Anyways, once he got there, he found his own posts were printed on money papers. Those were bloody valuable posts he got.</description></item><item><title>Extended resume, anecdotes and stories</title><link>https://adonese.sd/bio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/bio/</guid><description>You can download my resume here. If you want a longer more detailed with a little bit of anecdotes from here and there you can proceed with reading this page.
My intention is to document some stories that might go usually unnoticed and not quite suitable for the industry&amp;rsquo;s resume format.
Independent Projects, 2021-Present After leaving Sudan due to the civil unrest in April 2021 and resettling in the UAE, I embarked on a series of self-directed ventures.</description></item></channel></rss>