<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pixyll</title>
    <description>A simple, beautiful theme for Jekyll that emphasizes content rather than aesthetic fluff.</description>
    <link>http://pixyll.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://pixyll.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Associated legendre functions</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;its-just-anothe-empty-placeholder&quot;&gt;It’s just anothe empty placeholder&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 23:15:19 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://pixyll.com/project/alf/2016/03/01/placeholder/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pixyll.com/project/alf/2016/03/01/placeholder/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GeoidApp - Things could never be easier!</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;its-just-another-placeholder&quot;&gt;It’s just another placeholder&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Let’s see what I can do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 15:31:19 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://pixyll.com/project/geoid-app/2016/02/20/geiodapp/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pixyll.com/project/geoid-app/2016/02/20/geiodapp/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Spherical harmonics</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-disclaimer&quot;&gt;A DISCLAIMER&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This post isn’t intended to be comprehensive, full of math notations, weird concepts, formal language whatsoever!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ll try to use as less math notations as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is just for adding other bullets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;physics-is-boring-math-is-even-worse-both-are-you-kidding-me&quot;&gt;Physics is boring, math is even worse! Both? Are you kidding me?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s face it! We all hate physics classes. Most of them was too intuitive that makes you react like? Whaaat?
When you asked why bodies are falling? Else, are just to hard to be expalined. Physics relies heavily on mathematics, without it, it’s just a philosphy. In this post I’ll try to make things as simple as possible but not simpler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the default action to search wikipedia for an article of whatever you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;spherical harmonics are a series of special functions defined on the surface of a sphere used to solve some kinds of differential equations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have we learned something? Not sure, let’s jump to other part&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Spherical harmonics are functions defined in terms of spherical coordinates and are organized by angular frequency…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason for being no, is that there are already a lot of prerequisites, that’s great actually, assuming that you’ve a general idea about them. You should have an idea about &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;differential equations&lt;/code&gt; and how they relate to it, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;angular frequency&lt;/code&gt;! What if I don’t have an idea about them? Or I just failed to link them? This post is for that reason!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess that gives me a good to reason to write this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-the-heck-are-spherical-harmonics&quot;&gt;What the heck are spherical harmonics?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all know what sphere is, and we probably heard the word &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;harmonic&lt;/code&gt; a few times in music. They both seem too intuitive, but there inlies the problem.
Being too intuitive makes it very hard, I mean can you describe for someone why &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;1 + 1 = 2&lt;/code&gt;? It’s really hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a math perspective, a function is a called a harmonic if it satisfys Laplace’s equation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;\nabla ^ 2 f = 0&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-i-can-find-them-in-real-life&quot;&gt;Where I can find them in real life?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;are-they-that-important&quot;&gt;Are they that important?&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 15:31:19 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://pixyll.com/project/2016/02/20/spherical-harmonics/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pixyll.com/project/2016/02/20/spherical-harmonics/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
