<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-10T23:48:50+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">adonese’s Blog</title><subtitle>Think. Act.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">A friend of mine was faced with his facebook’s posts being printed on money papers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/23/a-friend-of-mine.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A friend of mine was faced with his facebook's posts being printed on money papers" /><published>2018-01-23T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/23/a-friend-of-mine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/23/a-friend-of-mine.html">&lt;p&gt;Money’s paper is a special type of papers that only used by authorized companies. It is typically used in the company’s official documents e.g., contracts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine (a bad one that actually thinks our governors are villain, screw you anti-progression), he was being summoned in response to his recent posts. Anyways, once he got there, he found his own posts were printed on money papers. 
Those were bloody valuable posts he got.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t actually ask him about their conversation, though I will fake one for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My villain friend: Hi Sir,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good ol’ guy: Oh dear, please have a seat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a moment of silence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good ol’ guy: I can see your confusion. We brought you here for some inquiries regarding your recent posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My villain friend: Oh, is that true. On what post/s are you interested?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good ol’ guy: Ah yes, can you come closer to look at them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My villain friend was apparently shocked to see his own posts were printed on these sophisticated papers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My villain friend: Those are not mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good ol’ guy: No, they are. We have printed all of your posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My villain friend interrupting, was that necessary. I mean you can just summon me and show them on a screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good ol’ guy: And now you are calling us idiots. Great. This is the kind of behavior we’d like to fix. Anyway, cut the shit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(END OF CONVERSATION)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I have not seen any posts from that villain friend since then. Our leaders are working day by night to our benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the background, I heard these rhythem “وأين صديقي حسن”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Money’s paper is a special type of papers that only used by authorized companies. It is typically used in the company’s official documents e.g., contracts.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A year at University of Khartoum</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/28/a-year-at-uofk.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A year at University of Khartoum" /><published>2017-10-28T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2017-10-28T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/28/a-year-at-uofk</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/28/a-year-at-uofk.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ve always been dreaming of teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked as a teaching assistant at University of Khartoum, Geomatics Engineering department. I’ve TAed different classes–mostyl computational/programming ones. It was very nice experience, I couldn’t be more happier. Though, I have some notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;national-service&quot;&gt;National Service&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The national service is the single most evil, human rights violation thing has ever been done. Our governers are literally using us to cover for their economical failures. The national service is a one year that each graduate student should serve in military. Usually, people prefer to do their national service in non-military places. That was exploited pretty well bad by the government sector.
In my case, I wasn’t physically fitted to do my national service in a miliant facility. Luckily, I met all the requirements to be accepted at UofK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;some-notes&quot;&gt;Some notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my first semester, I have TAed &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/view/se522&quot;&gt;Phyiscal Geodesy&lt;/a&gt;, 5th year students; &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/view/se412&quot;&gt;Adjustment Computations&lt;/a&gt;, 4th year.
I’m do not intend to write a detailed post about each class, I might do that later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I think that physical geodesy is the &lt;em&gt;toughest&lt;/em&gt; class ever. Students find huge difficulty in understanding the class materials. I’ve tried to ease the course by adding more programming exercises. E.g., the class project was about building a program to compute the geoid.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strike&gt;Most of students suffer much in mathematical intensive classes. I suspect that might be because the way courses are offered: You don't get to choose what courses you want to take.&lt;/strike&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Many of mathematical classes are poorly taught. They are not oriented towards engineering. Compared these courses to any of MIT’s for instance. In our particular case, geodesy heavily relies on physics, calculus, linear algebra, and differential equations. Well, on papers, &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; four year students have already taken these courses. The problem is, in my opinion, in the way that courses been taught. I still remember my linear algebra tutorials. We were so into proves. I have had solved many of Schaum’s problems. However, these skills were totally irrelevant to my field of study. The same applied to statistics and probabilities. Did you know that, college statistics are still taught with the same &lt;em&gt;“what is the mean? There are four oranage balls and five red balls in a basket, what is the probability of grabbing a red ball”&lt;/em&gt;. That is not helping at all.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I don’t agree to the 70 final exam and 30 class work policy. It is very ridiclous. It encourages students to &lt;strong&gt;only&lt;/strong&gt; study for the final exam. I have seen that, I’ve done it, too.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lack of communication between students and their instructor. Well, this might not be the biggest problem, but it is still there.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Many students do not know how to use email.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Students cheat all the time. You may not believe that, but I well known Imam (Sheikh), have given a fatwa that&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Copying answers from your friends is not Haram.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Well, while others don’t need that fatwa anyway, but I’m just trying to help you understand how our problems are fundamental. Just to be clear, that Imam’s fatwa was about cheating in tutorials and homeworks not in exams. Cheating in exams happens occurs also at a scary level. Every year, a few students got &lt;em&gt;caught&lt;/em&gt; and suspended for an year or two because of cheating cases. Many other cases occured but they were ignored. I will get to cheating point later.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of others, I might add as we go, or discuss them in the forum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;things-we-have-tried-to-do&quot;&gt;Things we have tried to do&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few things I have tried to do. Just to be clear, they are used in other institutions, so I have no credit for any of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Piazza is an online forum for courses discussions and announcements. It helps students to get in touch with the course instructors, and also help the course instructors to know how their students are doing in the course. The good thing is, we didn’t have to make any posters on the department’s walls, or call some student to tell the others that there will be a test on Wednesday, and some students tell you that they hadn’t been told. It was solved! The unfortunate bad thing is, some students find it too difficult to register, or use the website. Though, I clearly remember I have given them a fast ten minutes on how to use Piazza.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I believe that assignmets are the best way for students to understand any computational class materials. So, instead of giving them a 30-minutes to solve a toy problem and then collect their works, I made them assignments that needs more then just a few minutes to solve. Some professors didn’t agree with this idea. They urged that we’re just giving the students extra days to cheat from each others. Cheating happens, a lot. There is no clear policy on how to deal with cheating cases in e.g., tests, mid-terms, or in assignments.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Papers are hard to deal with. I urge that they don’t contribute too much to student’s writing skills. They might be used in the first year, but I totally don’t get why they are still used in senior years. I have tried to avoid hardcopy assignments as much as I can. Students were not allowed to submit their assignments in hardcopy format at all. (Except for the very very rare situations.) PDF rocks!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Students were asked to write their assignments using LaTeX. LaTeX is really nice in that the user doesn’t need to worry about the styling. While the students had had terrible nights dealing with LaTeX, the reward was very huge in their theses.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Grading is the most horrible thing to do. It takes a lot of time and effort. One might biased. We used &lt;em&gt;gradescope&lt;/em&gt; to handle students’ submissions and release assignments. Well, it works very well for me, however, it was a nightmare for some students. One told me that he had had spent four days trying to submit his assignment. Gradescope definitely is not that difficult. Again, students really lack many things.
  One nice thing I liked about gradescope is autograding for programming assignments. While I didn’t have the time to setup one for the course (I had to build a docker version for the programming language, etc. Docker was blocked for the Sudan, and I hadn’t had a great internet connection to do the VPN+other docker build steps.)
  Autograder will definitely save you a lot of hours, and it’s biased-free, too.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Gradescope was also great in controlling the assignments submissions. You can specify the release day, and the due. It will magically close after the due. Students can also submit a regrade request through gradescope (they were seeing their grades for each submission). We hadn’t use that, anyone needed to regrade.
  One thing I noticed about the release, due thing is: many students submit only on the last day. Even though they already completed the assignment. I had to tell them that they can submit at any time between the release date and the final date!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The grades for each assignment and other course works were all published to the students, and they were encouraged to ask for any revision. That really helped me to make things transparent between me and the students. It is your right to know exactly your marks. We are human, we make mistakes all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In all the tutorials I have not taken any attendance. I still cannot get this idea. I mean, if someone doesn’t want to attend, why are we forcing them inti doing that? That definitely will not help them understand the materials. Is not this the goal of what we are doing? I was worried that no one would attend, however, that just didn’t happen! I think that students are mature enough to decide whether they want to attend this lecture or not. Attending lectures/tutorials should not be the way how we assess them. &lt;em&gt;Maybe&lt;/em&gt; they were bored, or tired, or on a bad mood, or even they are just- &lt;em&gt;God help me&lt;/em&gt; -don’t need to attend at all!
  Don’t you think that taking attendance is time consuming?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes-for-students&quot;&gt;Notes for students&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey there! How are you doing? Here is the thing. I once said that, your time is more precious than ours (as instructors), and that we are doing everything for you. I still believe in that. College is an invesment for you. It is five years of your life–not to mention the tuition and living fees. Try to learn as much as you can. Try to connect with people inside your institution and people from outside. Be active in Engineer’s Week and other activities. These are the things that will shape your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your professors and TAs are not evil (sick) persons. Why not go to and ask them about relevant problems to their field, or career questions, etc. They have such a great experience, they will definitely help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was a student, we haven’t had too much of connections with both professors and lecturers. It might be a problem related to us (or me). As a TA, I have tried to connect to as much students as I could. I did that because it is healthy for the learning process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes-for-my-fellow-tas&quot;&gt;Notes for my fellow TAs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi dudes! How is it going?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know you are not doing fine at all. You are working in a full time position, and having a generous salary of 150 sdg (7.5 USD)! Things couldn’t be any better!
I totally feel your pain. TAs are the most crucial part in undergrad studies. You have to do the tutorials, the grading, and then sometimes midterms, and the exams, etc. You are doing everything. And, you are totally not appreciated. For me, and probably for most of you, I had to depend on my family for living. 150sdg is just shameful. It would be more appropriate if were paid something that covers our living expenses. Just living expenses. At some part you just be like why the &lt;strike&gt;fuck&lt;/strike&gt; am I doing this? Cannot I just drop my work and start working in other place? Teaching is really tough. TAs responsibilities are way too much. Having known all of that, students have nothing to do with this: we have to work very hard to give them proper materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes-for-the-administration-guys&quot;&gt;Notes for the administration guys&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to be more formal here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote this post as a summary of my work at University of Khartoum. These notes were never meant to hurt, attack anyone. I wish that you consider discussing these issues I presented and think of ways to address them. I wish that these notes highlight some of the problems we face at UofK.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Teaching at have always been one of dreams. I still cannot believe that I had a chance to teach at University of Khartoum, the most prestigious university in my country. In this post, I summarize my work there. There are a few things not good I wish to be resolved.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Internships at gndi</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/08/internships_at_gndi.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Internships at gndi" /><published>2017-10-08T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2017-10-08T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/08/internships_at_gndi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/08/internships_at_gndi.html">&lt;p&gt;We are very pleased to announce new internships at &lt;em&gt;gndi&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;G&amp;amp;I (&lt;em&gt;gndi&lt;/em&gt; for short) is a tech company that provides a wide range of geospatial solutions and services for corporates and for individuals as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-is-that&quot;&gt;Why is that?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This initiatives came as a response to one my &lt;a href=&quot;../2017-10-28-an-year-at-uofk/&quot;&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt;. Clearly there is a problem in our system. &lt;em&gt;There is no systematic way of getting a job&lt;/em&gt;. Every year, tons of peoples are graduating from colleges. Industry cannot cover this number of graduates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;internship-programs&quot;&gt;Internship programs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internship period is three months. Our interns will work on various projects. Here are just a few examples of some the things we might do (also listed here for others to work on)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Building a visualization tool for geodesy. Just to make things simple, we will only focuss on the materials from Ahmed Abdalla’s lecture notes and Rapp’s.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;GPS on Android. Seems to be easy peasy? Well, let us see.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Articles in Geomatics Engineering, tutorials, how-tos, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of our works will be open source and freely available for anyone to use and contribute. That is not even the best part. We, we those very awesome interns, will work together to give back. We will be giving workshops and tutorials on these technologies for the rest of their friends. 
We are also creating Geodesy Study group. We have many reasons as to why this study group is important. We need people to &lt;em&gt;understand&lt;/em&gt; geodesy and thereafter apply it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After three months, I will write another post describing our work through this internship. Before wrapping up this post. There is a good reason why I insisted on choosing students from Geomatics department. I graduated from this department and I taught at it too. I have a strong claim to know its problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice--warning&quot;&gt;We are not discriminating other disciplines. (Certainly we are not &lt;em&gt;disciplinists&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly encourage other big companies to try this out. I know that industry no long trusts academia (in Sudan). However, even in places where higher education is very robust, students also get to do internships. This is how things work. Unfortunately, educational institutions don’t have any plans on how to resolve this issue. They just throw their grad students away. It is no longer their responsibility. But let us just forget all that. It is as simple as this: industry needs good grad students. In order to have qualified students, they need to put what they were taught in practice. In our case, companies offers &lt;em&gt;training&lt;/em&gt; positions instead of &lt;em&gt;internships&lt;/em&gt;. The thing is, they are not the same: not in the job responsibilities, not in any aspect. Internships, on the other hand, offers those applicants a true job experience. That happens under a mentor, but still they got &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; more, and hence &lt;em&gt;learn&lt;/em&gt; more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another aspect I’d like to mention is about undergrad qualifications. There are many incredibly talented and ambitions students. They are just waiting there for you to make the move. Giving them that chance, not only will help them in their career, it will also help you very much. Trust, they can do all kinda of crazy things. All kinda of crazy things.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We are pleased to announce new internships at gndi. The internship program will be for college students (for now, we are only geomatics engineers.)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WTF are you here?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/08/08/my_hate.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WTF are you here?" /><published>2017-08-08T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2017-08-08T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/08/08/my_hate</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/08/08/my_hate.html">&lt;p&gt;Why are you so mean?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Why are you so mean?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">gndi E-learning Platform</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/06/01/gndi-elearning.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="gndi E-learning Platform" /><published>2017-06-01T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2017-06-01T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/06/01/gndi-elearning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/06/01/gndi-elearning.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;e-learning-rocks&quot;&gt;E-learning rocks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several reasons to use e-learning based system as oppose of the classical ones. Hosting all the course materials online can help our students a lot. They will find the materials of the course available 24/7. But that will also help us, too. As an instructor (for both G&amp;amp;I and UofK), I found it to be very time consuming to maintain a class. However, when we moved our works online, things have changed. The online forum accompanied with the website help students answer each others’ questions–that saved me lots of time, and helped the class understand the materials much better. Not only that, I found it to be much easier to respond to the class questions. Students know where to write their problems, I know where to find them. I now know what questions (what part of the class they suffer at it much), and how can I address such problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;difficulties&quot;&gt;Difficulties&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good intentions are not enough. All of our work on this platform was to be open sourced. I was doing this project as a part of my work at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gndi-sd.com/about&quot;&gt;G&amp;amp;I&lt;/a&gt;. Since, I have other things to do at gndi, and we really do not have much of resources to sponsor this project. I had to do it all by myself. But that was not also the biggest problem. I was so into this project that I was actually able to finish it all by myself in a very short time. Our biggest problem was the fact that we couldn’t fund its cloud costs. &lt;em&gt;After that, I stopped working on it.&lt;/em&gt; To be honest our financial situation was very bad, and it was not meant to generate any revenue anyway, who would sponsor such a project? This why, even you have good intentions that should not be all you have. If you truly believe in your project, you have to seriously think of ways to secure its financial situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-funding-for-your-open-source-project&quot;&gt;Get funding for your open source project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the main reasons to write this post. I needed to help anyone in the future to succeed in their open source applications. While I admire that you do it just because you love it/for fun. I still believe it is your responsibility to secure your open source financial resources. I think that is as important as making your program bug free. In both cases you cannot guarantee that, though you just try as much as you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addressing this problem, I will try to make my suggested solutions as relevant to Sudan [my country] as possible, though some solutions apply to any place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kickstarter, it is very well known for this kind of projects. Notice that, in Kickstarter, you only taking funding just once. This should be ideal in cases where your biggest problem is the initial costs. [it has a technical term I forgot.]&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gofundme. The same as Kickstarter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are probably ton of these, some of them with similar ideas. You may try search for similar ones local to your region, you’d probably find funding much easier from them. 
What I really would like to highlight here is other type of donations that I believe to be much better than the one before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;National grants for research. This is usually sponsored by the Higher Education Ministry in each country. While in Sudan, it is quite uncommon to have such a grant (there is not actually), in almost all countries such grants existed. This how research is done anyway. This grant is usually covers many of your running costs and the initial costs too. You will probably receive the funding through different periods for a fixed amount of time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Not very different from the one before, you might actually find it much easier to get a grant from an institution that is close to what you are trying to build. In our case, we are currently trying to get a fund from the ministry of forests and (really long name). One of &lt;a href=&quot;https://georxiv.github.io&quot;&gt;our projects&lt;/a&gt; happens to be similar to what the ministry was trying to do.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can also ask people for donations, but you should not rely on it only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-marks&quot;&gt;Final marks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maintaining an open source project is not easy at all. One need to consider many factors. In this post I tried to highlight different ways to help you maintain your project. Feel free to ask any questions and suggest other ways for funding.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In G&amp;I, we decided to level up the way classical training centers typically operate. We started our very first beta version of our new product, and here are our findings. To the best of our knowledge, no similar projects have been done before.</summary></entry></feed>