<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ranting on adonese's Blog</title><link>https://adonese.sd/tags/ranting/</link><description>Recent content in ranting on adonese's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 19:52:20 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adonese.sd/tags/ranting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tax Bracket Creep</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/tax-bracket-creep/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 19:52:20 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/tax-bracket-creep/</guid><description>I never thought there was actually a name for this which adds to how fiasco the whole thing is. But back to one of my earliest companies, my colleague had a very interesting encounter. After months of working really hard he felt the need to ask for a much deserved raise. So went by the HR and completed everything and they told him that he&amp;rsquo;ll get a raise as per the company&amp;rsquo;s ladder effective next month.</description></item><item><title>Being the eldest brother</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2023-04-06-brothers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2023-04-06-brothers/</guid><description>i was talking to online friends recently about what better dictates an older brother. The reponses i was swarmed with was nothing less than helpful and wholesome. Thanks a lot fellas.
Yet my very initial thoughts were unanswered, partly because it is actually me who&amp;rsquo;s supposed to answer them. The question was not really how to become a good older brother but more of why I feel i&amp;rsquo;m lacking.
I will go with the standard template: guidance, support, being present and being there for them.</description></item><item><title>what makes a company culture</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2023-03-04-what-is-a-culture/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2023-03-04-what-is-a-culture/</guid><description>Sometimes i legit be wondering about life. What is life? What is the whole point? What is the point of living? This is not a question that i can answer, nor is it a warning sign about my mental situation. I&amp;rsquo;m good thank you. But, this mundane, routine thing is becoming extremely irritating. An important person to me used to say that they were a virtual person in the process to become an individual.</description></item><item><title>Resignations</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-06-28-resign/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-06-28-resign/</guid><description>I have a decision making problem. I&amp;rsquo;m super good at making on-spot hard decisions. But i suck at making casual decisions: i take REALLY long time deciding between two types of water bottles.
A friend of mine resigned from their job and that took me by surprise. Never in my career had i resigned from my job, really.
2017-2018 first professional employment type: i worked as a part-time TA and researcher at UofK, my contract was for year.</description></item><item><title>Technology is scary</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-05-09-technology-is-scary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-05-09-technology-is-scary/</guid><description>Technology scares me, and don&amp;rsquo;t even get me started on how AI and that crazy shit have serious consequences that we are not adapted, that we have not considered at all. Tech companies emphasized their own revenue over making the humanity better &amp;ndash; errr making its users better. And those incentives don&amp;rsquo;t align with what the actual users want.
For example, a keyboard software. Let&amp;rsquo;s say google&amp;rsquo;s GBoard. It is fantastic, it is smart enough to predict and corrects their typing mistakes.</description></item><item><title>My birthday</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-05-08-birthday/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-05-08-birthday/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m in awe. I&amp;rsquo;m grateful for all of you guys, I&amp;rsquo;m grateful to my parents, siblings, close friends and amongst them my online friends. I will write back about my feelings later. But you made a soul happy.</description></item><item><title>Taking breaks</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-03-18-breaks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-03-18-breaks/</guid><description>I argue engineers and managers to actively seek to shorten work days and work hours. 9-5 / 5 days is such an arbitrarily concept and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t translate at all to productivity, in fact counter to that it is the most unproductive thing we might ever have.
Apart from the common wisdom to avoid burnouts, breaks are really super important. I argue against us having 5-days work scheme. It is way too much, it is quite useless too, and we lose lots of productvity and peak-performance and creative thinking, just to ensure that employees stay longer in the offices.</description></item><item><title>Robots</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-03-04-robots/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-03-04-robots/</guid><description>I argue that people almost turn to the robot mode when they are subject to a very mundane routinic type of daywork. Robot or the executor mode is the safest bet: you don&amp;rsquo;t get to think a lot, you don&amp;rsquo;t get to take risks, you just rebeat and always take-on the easy routes. That is fine and can get things done. You don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily want your Tirhal driver to be creativing about driving&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>A mattress</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-01-14-a-matt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-01-14-a-matt/</guid><description>I just noticed the single thing i have been dreaming to have is a matt. That is ridicluos i know, but I digged a little bit deeper to understand why.
Settlement. The reason i have been so focusing on the matt is that i truly wanted to settle, to have a home and the feeling that comes with it. But i couldn&amp;rsquo;t get anyone.
Now, i actually have the money to buy a matt, a nice lovely good one.</description></item><item><title>what is the point</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-01-05-what-is-the-point/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2022-01-05-what-is-the-point/</guid><description>Sometimes i legit be wondering about life. What is life? What is the whole point? What is the point of living? This is not a question that i can answer, nor is it a warning sign about my mental situation. I&amp;rsquo;m good thank you. But, this mundane, routine thing is becoming extremely irritating. An important person to me used to say that they were a virtual person in the process to become an individual.</description></item><item><title>A Date</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-11-19-moving-on/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-11-19-moving-on/</guid><description>The fact i still have my ex&amp;rsquo;s gifts is nothing short of a surprise to me. i still have:
her mug a lovely backpack an oracle speaker pocket shoes jalabya على الله Up until a few days ago, i kept a present i was meaning to give it to her (though i didn&amp;rsquo;t), before i gave to a friend. The truth is, i suck at keeping things around, i mean even if i want to, it is just so difficult for me to keep things.</description></item><item><title>A Date</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-10-22-a-date/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-10-22-a-date/</guid><description>Just to confirm: i have dated before, i kinda did the whole process so i&amp;rsquo;m very well familar with how dates are practically been conducted. The only problem is i usually was more or less invited to the dates and that what is making things this complex.
Why dating has became more difficult? Or, is it just me? Well, this really and truly is a personal issue, but one way of reasoning about the issues i ran into &amp;ndash; the bugs, is by speaking them out loud (usually to myself or with a colleague / friend, but you gotta do what you got.</description></item><item><title>hiring</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-10-09-lets-talk-about-hiring/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-10-09-lets-talk-about-hiring/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about hiring. Also hiring&amp;rsquo;s nuts. i have listened to Mohamed Mudather&amp;rsquo;s video about hiring (Kutti is the CEO of Orooma, popular recruitment company in Sudan). One of the things he mentioned:
you don&amp;rsquo;t have to have your guy at said company to hire you and companies are struggling to recruit candidates. So, if that was the case, then why engineers and even great ones are struggling to get hired?</description></item><item><title>bad practices and dirty code</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-10-02-dirty-code/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-10-02-dirty-code/</guid><description>i&amp;rsquo;m back to writing again. Hooray! Something&amp;rsquo;s been coocked aight?
Today i want to talk about a few things i hate about programming. Lots of enthusiastic programmers fall into this trap that is: 🥁🥁🥁 clean code! I don&amp;rsquo;t know of anything that is as subjective as clean code. You just cannot say whether this code is clean or not. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense at all.
java fuck java. Honestly, whenever i have a conversation with a java developer and no matter how senior they are it is always the same topics: best practices, clean code, and design patterns.</description></item><item><title>Let us change the tone</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-06-19-ngos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2021-06-19-ngos/</guid><description>I worked with some Non Government Organizations (NGOs) for some time, not too much to draw any conclusion, but long enough to get to notice some patterns. They are all seem to be well spoken, smart, and have it figured out. They know what they are doing, and they all have this same accent, for the lack of a better word.
The problem when we all have the same perspective, the same way of thinking, the books method.</description></item><item><title>The non-achievers</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-12-31-non-achievers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-12-31-non-achievers/</guid><description>So it is a new year, huh? You suddenly find your friends achieving really cool things and you feel like you have not done any thing. This post is for you, for US.
I don&amp;rsquo;t think life is a discrete function, and treating it that way might be the source of this optimizing for dopamine.
Success is not linear, in the journey of your life you will have far more failures than your successes.</description></item><item><title>9-5</title><link>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-09-04-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adonese.sd/post/2020-09-04-work/</guid><description>I have not written any post recently (4 months since my breakup post). I want to use this article to discuss some of the ideas i have about &amp;ldquo;work&amp;rdquo;, and by work i mean professional work. I won&amp;rsquo;t be citing anything (at least for now since i&amp;rsquo;m using this post to get away from working so yeah), so take everything here with a hugge grain of salt.
Corona has changed a lot and many of big software companies have moved to a permanent remote work setup.</description></item></channel></rss>